本字幕第一版由Community-137制作 同时发布于GitHub和SubHD 参与的成员有
带我们离开这 我来拖住他们
Get us out of here. I'll hold them off.
[翻译] Otter   走吃元   季叽馥疾己   Ng   Chrim   NPC   [校对] fuga   se9fault
转载请务必保留字幕信息 Community-137不对任何利用本字幕生成的视频负责
我叫Beth Smith
My name is Beth Smith.
告诉你的虫子头头们 反抗组织不会消亡
Tell your top bugs the Defiance lives on.
好的 好的
I will. I will.
本字幕是翻译习作的副产品 仅供学习、研究之用 欢迎RM爱好者交流完善译文
Blade：刀刃，这个词也出现在电影《银翼杀手》的片名Blade Runner中
我能让你成为传奇 Blade Smith
I'll make you a legend. Blade Smith.
- Beth Smith - Beth Beth Beth Smith
- Beth Smith. - Beth. Beth. Beth Smith.
好吧 我天 这名字也太普
Okay, God, it's just such a plain --
如果在观看中遇到任何错误翻译 诚邀您前往GitHub参与改错 该项目的地址是
我正试着给你的名字找个助记法
I'm trying to come up with a mnemonic device.
你可以把它和死里逃生联系在一起
You could connect it to not dying.
https://github.com/Community-137/Rick-and-Morty-Chinese-Subtitles 非常 非常 非常 期待您的参与
我明白 我明白 按理说这应该很刻骨铭心的
I know, I know! You think that would sear it right in,
但你名字的易忘度真是爆表了
but it just speaks to the sheer forgettability.
哦 天 我 我 我 呃 太抱歉了
Oh, God. I-I-I'm, uh, so sorry.
呃 呃 哦 天
Uh, uh, oh, God.
首字母是
Starts with a  --
恭喜贵政府 企业 或恐怖组织 喜得这件
Congratulations to your government, business, or terror cell on its acquisition of
Xamaxax牌NX-5行星清洁器
the NX-5 Planet Remover by Xamaxax
由威格牛仔裤特别赞助
in partnership with Wrangler jeans.
NX-5业界领先的
The NX-5's industry-leading
超光速粒子束能以NX-4S两倍的速度消灭行星
tachyon beams eliminate planets twice as fast as the NX-4S
只耗一半的的电力并且绝无内置致命设计缺陷
with half the battery and zero built-in fatal design flaws.
你没有听错 再没有秘密后门让人开一枪就爆炸
That's right. No more secret hole that blows the whole thing up when you shoot it.
你的敌人也许会说这不公平
Your enemies will say it's unfair.
- 但我们要说时候正好 - 见鬼
- We say it's about time. - Damn it.
我们拼死拼活为的就是这么
We risked our lives for that?
你尽力了 也许你需要休息一下
You did your best. Maybe you need a break.
- 你就不想念地球吗 - 我用不着想念它
- Don't you ever miss Earth? - I don't have to miss it.
技术层面讲 我仍在地球上
I'm technically still there.
我爸造了个完美克隆人替代我
My dad made a perfect clone of me to take my place.
天 那个Rick
Boy, that Rick.
所以 要是你真的回去
So, if you do go back,
那个克隆人会怎样
what happens to the clone?
它有 比方说 一个接近触发装置
Does it have, like, a proximity-triggered device
- 安在脖子里吗 - 谁在乎 我们弄好了吗
- in its neck? - Who cares? Are we done?
当然 除非你想让我拆除
Sure. Unless you want me to remove
你脖子里的接近触发装置
the proximity-triggered device from your neck.
觉得这是炸弹吗
Think it's a bomb?
天 如果你就是这样发现的
Man, what if this is how you found out
他压根不想让你回去
he never wanted you back,
而且他爱那个克隆人胜过爱你
that he loved the clone more than you?
那也太疯狂了吧
How crazy would that be?
疯狂并 并且自然也心碎着
Crazy and of -- of course soul-crushing.
对你而言 事实上针对这个我有对症的好东西
For you. I actually have something for that.
你 你想来点儿吗 不会上瘾
Y-You want some? They're nonaddictive.
并不 它们成瘾性极强
That's not true. They're totally addictive.
我是个烂医生
I'm a terrible doctor.
事实上针对这个我也有对症的好东西
I actually have something for that, too.
你想来点儿吗 不会上瘾 呣
You want some? Nonaddictive. Mmm.
我是个棒医生
I'm a great doctor.
王医生今天有个预约取消了
Dr. Wong had a cancellation today.
有人想去家庭心理辅导吗
Anybody up for a family session?
- 我可以去 - 求 求之不得
- I could do that. - I'm -- I'm down to clown.
喔 不确定能不能赶在心理辅导之前把治疗手偶做出来
Ooh, not sure my therapy puppet will be done in time.
那可真棒 因为她明确要求你
Great, because she specifically asked you
不要再带着手偶去了 爸
to stop bringing puppets. Dad?
我热爱心理治疗 尤其是家庭心理治疗
I love therapy, family therapy most of all,
但事实上我要分解了
but I am actually disintegrating.
- 哦 我天 - 喔 爸
- Oh, my God! - Whoa! Dad!
这是真的吗 我们做到了是吗
Is that really it? We did it?
是隐身腰带的效果
It's the invisibility belt.
喔 喔 喔 他碰着它们了
Whoa-whoa-whoa! He grazed them.
大概再过十秒就要开始疼了
That's gonna hurt in like 10 seconds.
- 谢谢啊 Morty - 为啥我要让你用得自在
- Thanks, Morty. - Why should I let you use it?
- 你都没让我用过 - 我能用用这条腰带吗
- You never let me use it. - Can I have the belt?
- 那一定会气坏Morty的 - 绝妙主意
- It would really piss off Morty. - Fantastic idea.
什么鬼 你个混蛋 交出来
What the hell?! You jerk! Give it!
隐身能力要分享使用 Jerry
Share the invisibility. Jerry?
喔 看来咬咬先生有工作要做了
Ooh, this looks like a job for Mr. Nibbles.
让我再粘一个眼睛上去
Let me just glue one more eye on.
我要杀了你
I'm gonna kill you!
我去 看上去你俩得就为什么
Woof. Looks like you two have to fight
控制不了孩子们吵一架了
about why you can't control your kids.
还好王医生正好有空
Good thing Dr. Wong's got an opening.
- 再见 - 你是个烂父亲
- Bye. - You're a bad father.
别任他挑拨离间
Don't let him divide us.
车库 启动应对家庭心理治疗模式
Garage, family therapy mode.
宝贝 你回来啦
Honey, you're back.
- 你看起来有点惊讶 - 你从没写信回来过
- You seem surprised. - You never wrote.
而且居然没爆炸是吧
And never exploded?
我听出的意思是 你觉得那是个炸弹
What I'm hearing is that you think that's a bomb.
所有看过的工程师都这么觉得
So does every engineer that's seen it.
工程师吗 宝贝 我确信每个穴居人
Engineer? Princess, I'm sure every caveman
见到微波炉都会以为那是个石头柜子
that sees a microwave calls it a rock cabinet.
搞发明的要义就是造出本来不存在的东西
The point of inventing is to make things that don't exist.
那你也造出个我不杀你的理由吧
Then whip me up a reason not to kill you.
爸 我们要去见王医生了
Dad? We're off to Dr. Wong's.
扫描她
Scan her.
爸
Dad?
好啊 玩得开心 小傻瓜
Okay, have fun, pumpkin.
抱歉我这个差劲父亲就不过去了
Sorry I'm a piece-of-shit father.
哈哈 好吧 这句自我厌恶已经帮我回本了
Oh, ha-ha! Well, the self-loathing buys a lot back.
Jerry 别带手偶
Jerry, leave the puppet.
我一定会取得突破的 Beth
It's a one-way ticket to a breakthrough, Beth.
她脖子里的装置是用来向你的装置
The device in her neck would have transferred
传输记忆数据的
a database of her memories to your device
之后再将她汽化
before vaporizing her.
这下都泡汤了
So much for that plan.
那为什么她 它
Why is she -- it --
为什么我会和Jerry复合啊
why am I back with Jerry?
她难道不是我的复制品么
I thought she was a copy of me.
她确实是你的复制品
She is a copy of you.
所以如果她跑回去找那个蠢货
If she ran back to that dingleberry,
得怪你
that's on you.
- 想喝一杯吗 - 随时
- Want to grab a drink? - All the time.
好姑娘
Good girl.
- 《猎捕掠食者》 - 什么鬼
- To catch a predator. - What the hell?!
热感成像镜 小婊砸
Thermal goggles, bitch.
妈妈说了要分享
Mom said share.
隐身能力怎么分享啊 你把眼镜摘了
You can't share invisibility. Take those off.
不
No.
所以等下我就直接去啦啦队训练那儿找你呗
So I'll just see you at cheerleader practice?
我要带个斗篷去吗
Should I bring a poncho?
好吧 你开个条件
Alright! State your terms.
腰带还我 眼镜拿走
Give back the belt. You take the goggles.
离开这里 一小时后交换
Go away. We trade in an hour.
成交
Deal.
这招如何 小婊砸
How do you like that, bitch?
这个新腰带可比旧腰带好多了
I liked it more than my old belt.
“小小大个子腰带青少年款”
"Tiny Big Man Junior"?
你本该选择分享的
You shoulda shared.
你在我家里干什么
What are you doing in my house?
我已经从主机那转悠出这么远了吗
Did I wander that far from my console?
他们应该在这些个VR眼镜上贴个警告标签的
They should put a warning on these things.
所以 我们冲破城门
So, we overrode the gates,
然后奴隶起义军就攻占了首都
and the slave rebellion took the capital.
- 挺酷的啊 - 相当酷啊
Pretty cool. Very cool.
我的女儿 经历着星际冒险
My daughter, having space adventures.
虽然有点往《星球大战》发展的味道
They are skewing a tad "Star Wars"-y, though.
别忘了找找乐子
Don't forget to have fun.
我是为杀你回来的 不是来听你意见的
Well, I came back to murder you, not get your notes,
不过拯救银河系时我会记得多放几个屁的
but I'll remember to fart more while I'm saving the galaxy.
好吧 是我让这一切成为可能的
Okay, I'm the one that made this possible.
- 咱们可不是在攀比啊 - 当然不
- It's not a competition. - Of course not.
但是纯粹好奇问一句 如果真要比比的话
Just curious, though, if it were,
“头号通缉犯”可以拿第一名吗
would "most wanted" be first place?
你怎么在对抗Gromflom星人
You're fighting the Gromflomites?
爸 他们想要接管整个银河系啊
Dad, they're trying to take over the galaxy!
银河系里的每个人都想接管银河系
Everybody in the galaxy tries to take over the galaxy.
在权力交替中独享世外桃源才是诀窍所在
The trick is to be left alone by whoever succeeds.
呃 不过现在你正到逞英雄的阶段
Eh, it's your hero phase.
我也经历过 你以后会成长的
I had one, too. You'll outgrow it.
不 你会变
No, you did.
我是不会变得对一切都漠不关心的
I'm not gonna outgrow giving a shit.
有消息源称 这些自称为
Sources tell us these aliens, who call themselves
新新银河联邦的外星人 将要炸毁这个星球
the Neeeew Galactic Federation, will blow up the planet
除非那个名字很无聊的女人出来自首
unless some woman with a very boring name gives herself up.
- 搞什么 - 你关心这些狗屎破事可关心得太好了
- Oh, come on. - Way to give a shit.
下次 记得别拿你的母星擦屁股
Next time, don't wipe it on your home planet.
我靠 他们要去追踪Beth了
Oh shit. They're gonna track down Beth.
你是说 Beth的克隆体吧
You mean... Beth's clone.
是啊 Beth的克隆体
Right. Beth's clone.
我 我不是这么说的吗
What -- What did I say?
能再见到你我是真心高兴的
It really was nice seeing you again.
哇哦 耶 冲啊 蜜蜂队
Whoo! Yeah! Go, Honey Bees!
练得不错 姐妹们
Good practice, girls.
记住 现在我们正处干旱
And remember, we are in a drought,
所以为了省水大家要组团
so be sure to shower as one big group
同时去洗澡喔
at the exact same time.
澡堂失火 澡堂失火啦
Shower fire! The shower's on fire!
靠边 姐妹们 我来搞定
Step aside, girls! I got this!
你这个魔鬼
You're a monster!
现在还想分享吗
Still wanna share?
Morty Smith 举起手来
Morty Smith, hands up.
你被逮捕了 罪名是反对
You are under arrest for crimes against
新新进步银河联邦政府
the New Improved Galactic Federation.
等下 啥 你是怎么做到的
Wait. What? How are you doing that?
你不是念力者吧 对吧
You're not a psychic, are you?
你有念力控制能力吗
Do you have psychic powers?
- 呃 有啊 - 力量很强大吗
- Uh, yes. - Are they strong powers?
我们只是想找你妈妈
We're just looking for your mother.
你不会有能力 比如 让我们心脏骤停之类的吧 会吗
You can't, like, stop our hearts, can you?
- 呃 我能 - 好吧 我们投降
- Uh, I can. - Okay, we surrender.
Jerry 你是否认同 使用手偶
Jerry, do you agree that the use of puppets
会显得自己又蠢又疯
makes you seem dumb and crazy?
我认为“疯”这个字在心理治疗的时候不便乱说吧
I don't think "crazy" is a responsible word to use in --
现在能说了 这就是疯了 你就是疯子
It is now. This is crazy. You're being crazy.
电视上的心理治疗都用手偶的
They do it in therapy on TV.
呵 电视台还给英国人颁烘焙奖呢 Jerry
Well, TV gives British people prizes for baking, Jerry.
- Tammy - 彤鸭 鳎米鸭 鳎米鸭
- Tammy? - Tonya? Tammya? Tammya.
嗨 Smith夫人
Hi, Mrs. Smith.
我更喜欢你这个发型
I like your hair better this way.
- 肚子还好么 - 啥啊
- How's the stomach? - What?
嘿
Hey!
我就“嘿”了一声
I only said "hey."
我也就能帮她到这份上了啊
It's not like I can do more than that.
虽然我很想宰了你
As much as I'd like to kill you,
但我的上司就你的反抗组织有话要问
my superiors have some questions about the Defiance.
我才没有 我有个反抗组织么
I don't have a -- I have a Defiance?
啊 天呐 我是克隆人
Oh, God, I'm a clone.
你就这样抗辩吗
That's your defense?
不 我的抗辩是“你咬我啊”
No, my defense is eat me.
嘿
Hey!
啊 怎么还打我
Ah! We've been over this.
我就“嘿”了一声啊
All I do is say "hey."
智能枪 把人类生命加进白名单
Smart guns, white-list human life.
以及那个心理治疗师
And the therapist.
Tammy 这间办公室 是帮我们一家
Tammy, this is the office where my family works
- 变得更融洽的地方 - 所以呢 就是个圣地了么
- to better itself. - What, and that makes it sacred?
并不是 所以我在此处部署了很多
No, it makes it a place I've rigged with a lot
声控的紧急逃跑装置
of voice-activated escape contingencies.
这些建议都很棒呢
These are all good points.
我得好好审视下自己了
I need to take a long look at myself.
我很想探讨下这个
I'd like to discuss that.
我才不探讨问题
I don't discuss problems,
我直接一把火烧掉
I incinerate them.
各位快上车
Everybody in the car.
我是说我家的各位 不是全世界
Everybody in my family, not the world.
老天爷啊 王医生 边界意识呢
Jesus, Wong. Boundaries.
这份工作配不上我
I'm better than this job.
你就不能直接造个传送门么
Can't you just make a portal?
你孩子还在地面上隐着形呢 Jerry
Your children are down there invisible, Jerry.
“造个传送门”么 我后面坐着的是年度好爸爸啊
"Make a portal"? Father of the year back here.
呵 真好意思说
Well, you're one to talk.
你说过我不是克隆人的
You told me I wasn't a clone.
你你你不是啊
Y-You're not a clone.
- 那那货是谁 - 呃 克隆人呗
- And who is that? - Uh, uh, a clone?
你何必克隆一个我出来
Why would you make a clone of me
然后把她打发到宇宙中去
just to send the clone into space?
你又不想离开 我就寻思
Well, you didn't want to go, and I thought,
“行吧 没问题”
"Okay, that's cool."
但转念一想 “你知道怎样会更有意思么 星际女儿如何”
But then I thought, "Well, you know what would be even cooler is a space daughter,"
就 就造了一个
s-so I made one.
我还在她脖子上安了个炸弹以防她回来
And I put a bomb in her neck in case she ever came back.
年度好爸爸
Father of the year.
她就不该回来
She wasn't supposed to come back.
那她咋回来了
Why did she?
呃 她发现了脖子上的炸弹
Well, she found a bomb in her neck.
是你你回来不
Wouldn't you?
- 年度好爸爸 - 你丫闭嘴
- Father of the year. - Shut up!
我对你的信任耗尽了
I'm tired of believing you.
- 我要去跟她谈 - 不 你不想
- I want to talk to her. - No, you don't.
Jerry 帮帮我啊
Jerry, do something.
嘿
Hey.
他跟我说你是那个克隆体
He told me you're the clone.
你觉得他是怎么跟我说的
What do you think he told me?
- 你是克隆体是吗 - 哇 天真且迷人呢
- You're the clone? - Wow, naive and attractive.
哇 疲倦却火辣呢
Wow, jaded and hot.
我知道这样教育子女不对
I know this is bad parenting,
但你们停止打架的话 爸爸就带你们去吃麦当劳
but if you stop fighting, you both get McDonald's.
那不如我把我的大脑崩了 从她开始怎样
How about I just blow my brains out, starting with hers?
好吧 那去温蒂汉堡 我们都爱温蒂
Okay, Wendy's. We love Wendy's.
温蒂汉堡貌似还给了我们广告费呢
I-I think they even gave us some money.
- 放下武器 - 别动 - 站住 趴下
- Drop it. - Don't move! - Freeze! Get down!
- 趴在地上 - 趴在地上 - 别动
- On the ground! - On the ground! - Don't move!
都给我闭嘴 你们说的全都他妈不一样
Everybody, shut up! You're all saying different shit.
等下 所以有两个她么
Wait, so there are two of them?
更重要的是 哪一个是我的
More importantly, which one is mine?
都不是 你个沙猪男
Uh, neither, chauvinist.
无所谓 都抓起来
Whatever. Take them both.
光还挺酷 但咱们谈谈条件吧
Cool beam. But let's bargain.
你们真正的目标是我
I'm the one you really want.
你说啥
Excuse me?
全宇宙最聪明的人
Uh, smartest man in the universe?
跨维度旅行的秘密
Secret to interdimensional travel?
问问你头头们去吧
Ask your bosses.
我的头头们都是虫子 Rick
My bosses are bugs, Rick.
老的都让你杀了 新的才到我一半年纪
You killed the old ones. The new ones are half my age.
他们明白只要让你落单 你就只是零威胁
They know if you're left alone, you're a non-threat.
- 啊哦 - 我们带走目标了
- Oofa! - We got the payload.
可以启动NX-5了
Fire up the NX-5.
地球要完蛋咯
Earth's going ta-ta.
你也许又该找个新宇宙了
You might want to do that thing where you find a new universe
然后自个儿吸屌去吧
where you can suck yourself off.
轮得到你来告诉我做什么吗
You can't tell me what to do.
真棒 他拒捕了 我们能朝他开枪了
Awesome. He resisted. We can shoot him.
- 啥 - 配合我 Jerry
- Wha? - Just go with it, Jerry.
所有人 放下枪 除了Jerry
Everybody, drop your guns -- except for Jerry!
傻逼 不愧是你
Fucking classic.
- 哦操 Morty - 还有Summer
- Holy shit, Morty. - And Summer.
我们 我们并肩作战了 这就是我们俩的人物弧
W-We worked together. That's -- that's our arc.
我们从姐弟 到隐形人 又进化到了并肩作战
We went from siblings to invisible to working together.
没有《公民凯恩》进化得那么好 但有啥可攀比的呢
It's not "Citizen Kane," but why compete
他跟这发生的事儿比起来 你懂的吧
with whatever's going on here, you know?
你搞得我得参加一场婚礼
You made me go to a wedding.
还杀了我最好的朋友 呃我应该先说这个的
And you killed my best friend. I shoulda said that one first.
恭喜地球正在被NX-5毁灭
Congratulations, Earth, on being destroyed by the NX-5,
由威格牛仔裤冠名播出
brought to you by Wrangler.
诶 我猜银河系的头号通缉哺乳动物
Ugh, guess the galaxy's most-wanted mammal
需要她爸爸给她换尿布了
needs her daddy to come change her diapie.
来吧孩子们 我们他妈的
Come on, kids, we have to go do
得整一段《星球大战》了
a fucking piece of shit "Star Wars."
Zeta 99-2号 注意
Attention, Zeta 99-2.
我们知道你的船是偷来的 立即退下
We know you have a stolen ship. Stand down.
哦 我现在又不是零威胁了吗
Oh, am I not a non-threat now?
喂 你还没获准降落
Hey, you are not cleared to land.
- 我们要开火了 - 坚守住阵地
- We will open fire. - Hold your ground, men.
你们会成为英雄
You'll be heroes.
Summer 试试看用你高中朋友的死脸扫描一下能不能解锁这道门
Summer, try unlocking that door by scanning your high-school friend's dead face.
额 我 我得尿尿
Uh, I have -- I have to pee.
尿地板上吧 这是个死星
Pee on the floor. It's a Death Star.
好吧 但不是有义军同盟 还有那什么什么嘛
Okay, but there's rebellion and then there's --
- 老爸 给你 - 太棒了
- Here, Dad. - Perfect.
我这样不对吗
What am I doing wrong?
呃 她的眼睛是闭上的 Morty 把她左眼扒开
Ugh, her eyes are closed. Morty, open the left one.
我来扒右眼
I've got the right.
她死得就像她活着的戏份一样拖沓
She died the way she lived, overserialized.
我去解救你们的妈妈和克隆体
I'm gonna rescue your mom and her clone
不告诉她们谁是谁
without revealing which is which.
你俩去找NX-5然后把它关掉
You two find the NX-5 and shut it down.
不过吧 别在尝试的途中死掉 地球有无穷多个呢
I mean, don't die trying. There's infinite Earths.
如果你们能救下这个 那还挺好的 是个飞来福
If you can save this one, it's gravy.
梦之队再度起航
Dream team rides again!
确实 我们就像卢克和莱娅
Oh, yeah, we're like Luke and Leia.
呃 抛开亲嘴的部分
Uh, except no kissing part.
换个别的有名的兄妹姐弟组合
What's another famous brother-sister team?
《战慄糖果屋》的汉塞尔和格蕾塔吗
Uh, Hansel and Gretel?
算了 那俩肯定上床了
Yeah, right, those two were fucking.
老爸 我们需要那个隐形腰带
Dad, we need the belt.
有你俩看着我尿不出来
I can't go with you guys watching.
- 你是隐形的啊 - 万一尿不隐形呢
- You're invisible. - What if the pee isn't?
算了 我们不需要隐形腰带了
You know what? We don't need invisibility.
并肩作战就是我们的腰带
Working together is our belt.
这就是我们的人物弧了 上吧
That's our arc. Let's do it.
我还要吹着口哨走呢
I'm gonna go ahead and whistle.
我的感觉就是这么棒
That's how good I feel.
天啊 我就知道
Oh, God. I knew it.
呃 这儿的地面不平
Ugh, this floor isn't level.
他们会虐待我们吗
Are they gonna torture us?
除非你打算告诉他们我知道些什么
Unless you plan on telling them what I know.
最后一次猜谁是克隆的机会了
Last chance to guess who was the clone.
你才是他女儿
You're his daughter.
你眼睛里也有那种
Just something about the eyes,
无耻的抛弃家庭的感觉
the shameless abandonment of your family.
那我又是怎么做到不带愧疚的呢
However can I live with myself?
我提个理论 我被你爸设计成了我行我素没有愧疚的人
One theory -- I was designed by your father to live with myself,
而这意味着 当时是你以自由意志决定的
which would mean you made a conscious choice
把梦想打碎了和着劣质红酒和恐龙意面往肚子里咽
to swallow your dreams with cheap wine and dinosaur pasta.
你知道Jerry就喜欢这种
You know that's the kind Jerry likes,
就像我知道你那仅有的该死梦想
same way I know the only Goddamn dream you'll ever follow
就是得到你垃圾爸爸的认可
is your shitty father's approval.
你给你的垃圾爸爸接柠檬水
You fetch your shitty father's lemonade.
你打扮得像你垃圾爸爸三十岁时候的样子
You cosplay as your shitty father in his 30s.
红色警报 红色警报
Red alert. Red alert.
Rick Sanchez
Rick Sanchez --
不如说是死亡警报 还有啥 还有啥
More like dead alert. What else? What else?
我在我记事本App里写了些东西
I wrote some stuff down in my Notes app.
让我找找
Let me just find it.
不管了 Beth 如果 如果你们俩有一个活着
Screw it. Beth, if -- if one of you is still alive,
你就是我的真女儿
you're my real daughter.
如果你俩都活着 别伤害另一个
If you're both alive, don't hurt the other one.
她只是个克隆 她不值得
She's just a clone. She's not worth it.
我来了 宝贝
I'm coming, baby.
- 那坨狗屎 - 那坨狗屎
- That piece of shit. - That piece of shit.
话说 我是回来杀他的
I came back kill him, you know.
我要帮忙
I'd like to help.
- 踢我眉心 - 从这儿吗
- Kick me between my eyes. - From here?
噢 难不成你为了省钱给Jerry买成长快乐 连瑜伽课都不上了吗
Oh, you dropped yoga so you could buy Jerry more Flintstones Vitam--
噢 我不太喜欢这个巨大的打斗仓
Oh, I do not like the looks of this giant fight chamber.
- 鸟人 - 我现在是凤凰人了
- Bird Person? - It is now Phoenix Person.
你和他们一伙了
You're working for them?
他们都对你做了些什么 BP
What did they do to you, BP?
我现在是PP了 Tammy在哪
It is now PP. Where is Tammy?
喔 别担心 我把她杀了
Oh, don't worry about her. I killed her.
- 我爱过她 - 真的吗 哈
- I loved her. - Really? Huh.
那我能给你起个别名吗
Then can I suggest, as an alternate name,
疯舔狗人
Crazy Pussy Whipped Person?
有意思 一直以来 我都好奇要是我俩打起来谁能赢
It's funny. I always wondered who would win if we ever fought.
那一直以来 你都是个损友
Then you were always a bad friend.
Morty 我们只有一个手雷
Morty, we had one grenade.
- 他有枪 - 算了吧
- He had a gun. - Whatever.
来吧
Come on.
- 你听到什么了吗 - 不重要
- Did you hear something? - Doesn't matter.
如果有人来了 那他们肯定是来停下这个激光的
If anyone's around, they're here to stop the laser,
他们要想动手的话 我们肯定会发现
and they can't do it without us seeing them.
合作是我们的腰带
"Working together is our belt"?
- 你把它给出去了 - 你说我们用不到了
- You gave it away! - You said we didn't need it.
真希望你没生出来过
I wish you were never born.
你还是意外怀孕呢
You were an accident.
为啥有些裤子没
How come some of the pants are --
NX-5没法摧毁威格牛仔裤
The NX-5 can't destroy Wrangler jeans.
那 是真的没法摧毁还是只是程序设计成这样
Like, it literally can't destroy them or it's programmed not to?
天 你说呢
Gee, what do you think?
你这个马医 杀虫也挺厉害
You kill good bug, for a horse doctor.
谢谢了 我
Thanks, me.
也许哪天我们可以像《天生一对》里面那样玩玩
Maybe we could do, like, a "Parent Trap" thing together sometime.
只要你指的是林赛·罗韩那版就行
As long as you mean the Lindsay Lohan version.
那肯定
Naturally.
你觉得他们会拿那些牛仔裤干什么
What do you think they do with all those jeans?
- 做成外套吗 - 这可不是要省牛仔布
- Make them into jackets? - It's not about conserving denim.
这是营销 就像 呃
It's marketing. Like, uh,
“NX-5 能摧毁整个星球
"The NX-5 destroys the whole planet
除了威格牛仔裤”
except for the Wrangler jeans."
因为它们太坚韧了 比激光还要坚韧吗
Because they're so tough. Tougher than the laser?
- 太傻了 - 但确实你就记住它了
- Stupid. - You're talking about it.
嗯 你说得对 我 我中计了
Mm, you're right. They -- they got me.
嘿 这里 看着我
Hey, over here. Look at me.
你有看到有个没穿裤子的小孩跑过去了吗
Did you just see a pantsless little boy run by?
我不会再吃你那套了
I'm not falling for that again.
我之前是隐形的 现在反过来了
I used to be invisible, but now I'm the opposite.
办了他 不是污污的那个办
Get him. But not in a weird way.
你愣是搞污了
You made it weird.
检测到NX-5联合赞助商
NX-5 corporate sponsor detected.
无法穿透威格牛仔裤
Cannot penetrate Wranglers.
质量过硬
Built too tough.
质量  过  硬
Built... too... tough.
我杀了他们 我在 我在屏幕外杀了他们
I killed them! I-I did -- I did it offscreen.
天杀的 Morty 把你内裤弄好
God damn it. Morty, fix your underwear.
我有那么几秒钟看到你的蛋了
I saw your balls for a second.
那是你的问题
That's on you.
我为什么不能见你的父母
Why can't I meet your parents?
我会很丢你的脸吗
Are you embarrassed of me?
不 他们会很丢我的脸
No, of them.
没想过会这样挂掉
Never thought this was how I'd die.
我们距离威尼斯还远着呢
We're nowhere near Venice,
你也不是个穿雨衣的侏儒
and you're not a dwarf in a raincoat.
退后 在我们痛扁他之前 你可不能杀了他 鸟人
Step back. You're not killing him till we kick his ass, Bird Person.
我的名字是凤凰人
My name is Phoenix Person.
没人会这么称呼你的 蠢货
No one's calling you that. Dumb.
一家人都这么喜欢找茬 但是又这么差劲 可真令我着迷
It fascinates me that an entire family can be this critical and suck this much.
停 鸟人
Bird Person, stop.
是我 那个Tammy小妞
It's me, that Tammy girl.
Tammy 真没料到
Tammy, this is unexpected.
我听说你死了
I was told you were dead.
那 百 分 之 百 不是真的
That is ab-so-lute-ly not true.
我比过去更活泛了
I'm more alive than I've ever been.
你的行为真怪异
You are behaving rather strangely.
我 怪么 哦 我天
Me? Strange? Oh, my.
又有谁正常呢 真的
Well, who's normal, really?
过来吧 你这个骨头中空的大羽毛脑袋
Now, come here, you big hollow-boned featherhead.
快来尝尝我甜美的屁股
Let me give you some of this sweet ass.
用手偶戏反败为胜
Saved the day with puppeting.
唯一像回事的人物弧
Only one with a decent arc.
他确实也有好的时候
He does have his moments.
妈 爸
Mom, Dad!
妈 我们做到了
Mom. Uh, we did it!
Morty变得超级可见
Morty became super visible!
Summer把我牛仔裤放激光里了
Summer put my jeans in a laser!
Morty 看看你的小蛋蛋
Morty, look at your little balls!
- 我知道 - 快让妈抱抱 孩子们
- I know! - Bring it in here, guys.
牛逼 这玩意是双涡轮的
Damn, this thing has twin turbines?
如果你让我开 我就原谅你遗弃我们
I'll forgive you for abandoning us if you let me drive it.
- 我无所谓 我本来只是打算给你些太空烟的 - 我喜欢有两个妈妈
- That works for me -- I was just gonna give you space cigarettes. - I love having two moms.
而我喜欢有两个老婆
And I love having two wives.
永远不可能 Jerry
Never gonna happen, Jerry.
那个百爪挠心的真相你们俩混蛋做好心理准备了么
You jerk-offs ready to get the answers to your burning questions?
- 这是什么 爸 - 显然是用来区分真假Beth的记忆
- What's this, Dad? - The memory of which Beth is real and which Beth is a clone, obviously.
你对自己整了摧心时刻那一出吗 你
You mind-blew yourself? You --
你居然还真不知道哪个才是你真正的女儿
You literally don't even know which of your daughters is real.
你当然会不知道了 我干嘛还吃惊呢
Of course you don't. Why am I surprised?
我敢说 你很希望我们想要从你那儿知道真相
I'm sure you'd love for us to need that from you,
但是我根本不在乎那小瓶里面是啥
but I don't care what's in that vial.
是 我也是
Yeah, me neither.
- 你横竖都是个人渣 - 所以呢
- You're a piece of shit either way. - So what,
经历了这么多之后 你们不想知道真相吗
After all this, you don't want to know the truth?
真相就是我们有更重要的事去做
The truth is we have more important shit to do
比如养大我们的孩子 消灭星际联邦
like raise our kids and stamp out the Federation,
这些看起来都跟你没什么关系
neither of which seem like they want anything to do with you.
Morty 小夏夏 至少你们会想知道谁是真的妈妈吧
Morty? Sum-Sum? You gotta at least wanna know who your real mom is.
不见得 Rick
Not really, Rick.
我们现在有俩特厉害的妈妈了
We have two badass moms now.
这也是一种双赢
It's -- That's kind of a win/win.
是啊Rick姥爷 别因为你在家里没了掌控权 就把我们卷进你的烂事里
Yeah, Grandpa Rick, don't drag us into your bullshit just because you're losing control.
我知道我想做什么
I know what I want to do.
- 我想要你做决定 - 什么
- I want you to decide. - What?
这是人生中唯一一次 我想让你做决定 爸
For once in my life, I want you to decide, Dad.
你是想让我留在这里 成为你生活的一部分呢
Do you want me to stay here and be part of your life,
还是想让我走呢
or do you want me to leave?
*我知道你尝试过*
*I know you tried*
*我知道你尽力了*
*I know you tried your best*
*是时候将这一切置之脑后了*
*And now it's time to put this all to rest*
嘿 吼 赌一把 赌一把啊
Hup! Ho! Big money, big money.
盯住她哦 变得真快
Eyes on the lady. Switcheroo.
哪个是哪个
Which one's which?
见鬼 我是个差劲的父亲
Holy shit. I'm a terrible father.
*一个遥远的声音*
*Oh, a distant voice*
至少我是个好朋友
At least I'm a pretty good friend.
看起来就剩你跟我了 伙计
Looks like it's just you and me, buddy.
好吧 好吧 再给你点时间
Okay, alright, we'll give you a little more time.
*有股力量想将我拖入深渊*
*There’s a force and it's trying to drag me down*
*深渊*
*Down*
*如果你去 那我会追随你的脚步*
*If you go then I'm going with you now*
Don't Look Back (feat. Kotomi & Ryan Elder) - Rick and Morty
*别回头 没什么可看*
*Don't look back, nothing left to see*
*把影子留在过去*
*Just leave the shadows in the past*
*如果我放手*
*If I let it go*
Community-137感谢您半年来的陪伴 我们第五季见
*我能摆脱这感觉吗*
*Can I shake this feeling?*
*就像那样*
*Just like that*
*我永远无法要回明天*
*Tomorrow's one day that I'm never getting back*
*但我能感觉到你*
*I can feel you though*
*将我从这梦中唤醒*
*Wake me from this dreaming*
再见 老朋友
Ah, goodbye, old friend.
我们玩得很开心 但我已经准备好再次露面了
We've had our fun, but I'm ready to be seen again.
- 什么鬼 - 我天 我去哪了
- What the fuck?! - Oh, my God! Where did I go?
哦 我勒个大槽
Oh, shitskis.
慢点
Slow down!
- 路上有一辆看不见的垃圾车 - 那可不咋地
- There's an invisible garbage truck in the road! - Yeah, right.
我还活着 我活--
I'm alive. I survi--
那啥 入乡随俗吧
I mean, when in Rome.
*看不见的垃圾车Jerry*
*Invisible Garbage Truck Jerry*
*这是个新剧*
*It's a new franchise*
婊子 你的工作就是和陌生人交媾
Bitch, your job is to have intercourse with strangers
并且把钱给我
and give me the money.
抱歉我叫你婊子 这里它是专业术语
Sorry I called you a bitch, it's a vocational term.
而不是我个人对你的评价
It's not how I feel about you personally.
什么 什 什什 啊
What the -- what -- what -- aah!
有人叫车了吗
Somebody call for a pickup?
我们去倒垃圾吧
Let's go take out the trash.
*看不见的垃圾车Jerry*
*Invisible Garbage Truck Jerry*
*这是个新剧*
*It's a new franchise*
*直到他没油了*
*Until he runs out of gas*
呃 合作得还不赖啦
Well, we had a good run.